Menu

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
|     |     |

Website Privacy Policy
======================

Sections

Copyright© 2003 Canadian Dental Association (CDA). All rights reserved.

This statement describes how we collect information from you or about you, why we collect this information, how we will use or disclose this information and how you can update or delete personally identifiable information collected about you from our records.

**IP Addresses**

There are several types of information we collect. For all visitors to the website, we collect and log your IP address. An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the internet. IP addresses allow computers and servers to recognize and communicate with one another. We collect IP address information to properly administer our system and to gather aggregate information on visitors to our site and how our site is being used, including the pages visitors are viewing.

To maintain your anonymity, we do not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information. We will use IP address information, however, to personally identify you when necessary to enforce our legal rights or when required to do so by law enforcement authorities.

* * *

**Cookies**

We may also place small data files, called "cookies," in the browser file of your computer's hard drive. These cookies automatically identify your browser to our server whenever you interact with the website. Most browsers automatically accept these cookies, but you usually can change your browser setting to prevent the acceptance of cookies. In addition, we usually collect the domain name of the server from which you are visiting. This can provide us with information relating to the sources of our traffic. Collecting this information does not allow us to personally identify you.

* * *

**Registration Information**

We also collect personal information that you choose to share with us in the registration and interactive portions of this website. This information may include personal information, e-mail addresses and your answers to questions. This information is only collected with your permission. We collect this information, should you decide to provide it to us, to provide you with the services and information being offered in accordance with CDA's main [CDA Privacy Policy](https://www.cda-adc.ca/en/important_notices/cda_privacy_policy/default.asp).

* * *

**E-mail Communications, Newsletters and Related Services**

We may occasionally send you informational e-mails or surveys. These e-mails will often include links to CDA's website or to the websites of other organizations. To enable CDA to tailor our communications to your interests, we may track the web links that you click on. This tracked information will only be used to analyze your interest in our communications, and in keeping with CDA's main Privacy Policy, will not be shared with any other organizations. Alternatively, if you wish to remain anonymous, you can access the web pages referenced in those e-mails by visiting CDA's website and your visit will not be tracked.

To stop receiving e-mail communications, e-mail your request to unsubscribe from CDA's electronic news service to [reception@cda-adc.ca](mailto:reception@cda-adc.ca?Subject=Unsubscribe%20from%20CDA%20electronic%20news%20service).

* * *

**Information for E-commerce Transactions**

Some areas of the website may allow you to conduct e-commerce transactions. In connection with these transactions, we securely collect data necessary to complete the transaction and that is furnished by you. This information may be furnished to a third party, under contractual privacy obligations to CDA, in order to facilitate the transaction.

* * *

**Aggregate Information**

We use general traffic, site usage, and length of stay information in reports to advertisers and firms with which we have a business relationship. This sort of information is shared only on an aggregated basis and does not personally identify you.

* * *

**Children's Privacy**

We do not permit registration by, nor do we collect personally identifiable information from, any person we actually know to be under the age of 18.

* * *

**Changing or Deleting Information**

CDA will be pleased to inform you of the existence, any use, and disclosure of personally identifying information, and provide you with access to that Personal Information, within 30 (thirty) days of a receipt of a written request directed by fax or mail to CDA, Manager Information Technology. To request a change or delete information that has previously been furnished by you to us, make that request in writing — by fax or by regular mail (not by e-mail) — to the Manager, Information Technology for CDA with the details of your request. Contact information is at the end of this statement.

* * *

**Other Sites**

Our privacy policies apply only to your use of this website (www.cda-adc.ca). The website contains links to other sites, including sites that may indicate a special relationship with us. While we do not disclose personably identifiable information to those operating these linked sites, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. You should read the privacy policies of each site you visit to determine what information that site may be collecting about you.

* * *

**Changes to Our Privacy Policies**

We may change the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policies at any time by posting revisions on the website. You agree to review the Privacy Policies each time you use the website so that you are aware of any modifications made to these policies. By accessing or using the website, you agree to be bound by all of the terms and conditions of the Terms of Use as posted on the website at the time of your access or use, including the Privacy Policies then in effect.

* * *

**Questions**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding the CDA's practices, please contact CDA by regular mail, by e-mail or by fax using the contact information listed below.

**Canadian Dental Association**  
1815 Alta Vista Drive  
Ottawa, Ontario, Canada K1G 3Y6  
Attention: Chief Privacy Officer  
  
Tel: (613) 523-1770  
Fax: (613) 523-7736  
E-mail: [reception@cda-adc.ca](mailto:reception@cda-adc.ca)

* * *

CDA website Privacy Policy September 8, 2003

-------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------

Copyright © 2024 Canadian Dental Association, Inc. All rights reserved.
